[SPEAKER_02]: And we both came out of college and never played minor league ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: That would be a real coincidence.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who scouted you down there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they didn't have much scouting for college players then.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we played them in the spring.
[SPEAKER_02]: We trained down there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And my coach, Bish, was from Wisconsin, and he kind of had some contacts there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they wrote him about me later.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, we didn't have any scouts to travel to.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's where we made the contact.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you grow up here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you born around Austin?
[SPEAKER_02]: Born in Austin.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did your dad play ball, or did you get all your athletic talents?
[SPEAKER_02]: Drag not.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sand a lot, high school, college.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you play, did they have a high school team?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they did have one in high school.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you went to, what years were you at Texas then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Quarter of 17, 18, 19, 20.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you major in?
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't graduate because I went in pro ball for that.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I came back and took the one semester in the fall.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then that's all I had time to do.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I looked like I was playing regular.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I didn't go back.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then again, I took part in a tour in the winter.
[SPEAKER_02]: But it's gone all winter.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I just had to go back.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did your parents like the idea of playing ball, or did they want you to finish school?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no, they left it up to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see how we sound here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, tell me about when you signed your first contract.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember who signed you and what your feelings were about that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was all settled by wire or mail between the White Sox and Daesh.
[SPEAKER_02]: and myself, and they just sent a contract down here after school that summer.
[SPEAKER_02]: I signed in the summer before I reported.
[SPEAKER_02]: In those days, you could do that in college.
[SPEAKER_02]: It wasn't a matter of signing a call and being ineligible.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I actually signed the contract, let's see, in the summer of 19, and I reported in June of 20.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that's... How'd you feel about that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they strike?
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a pretty good strike, because I didn't know, I kind of didn't expect, I thought I'd be burned out, because they had a great team, you see.
[SPEAKER_02]: They almost had a great team.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they had there until they threw the Sears away.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they had a pretty good outfit, and that was my break, is when they got kicked out, they had to rebuild.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was my break.
[SPEAKER_02]: If it hadn't been for that, I'd have been down, and I don't know when I'd have been back up, but I'd have been down instead of starting up again.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kid Gleason was still there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gleason was the man in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you report to him right away then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I joined him after school.
[SPEAKER_02]: I joined him in Philadelphia on the road, and I finished the road trip around.
[SPEAKER_02]: I stayed with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never did play much except, oh, I did pinch hit once or twice after a game was lost or something like that, you know, just put you in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Week to season, when these fellows get kicked out, they're not up late every day.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: The scandal hadn't broken yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, it broke last week.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had one more week to go.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's why it broke.
[SPEAKER_02]: Could you talk about the feelings of the players at that moment?
[SPEAKER_02]: What was it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it's been rumored.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, the thing has been rumored all year at different times.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I know at one time, I said,
[SPEAKER_02]: something to print in the paper.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you see, they kicked out Chick Daniels.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't come back the next year.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was supposed to be the ringleader.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they had so much poop on him gambling that he wasn't back.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, the rest of them were back, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So I, Sycott, who was one of the guys in Washington one day, was standing out in front of the hotel.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, what's all this rumor about
[SPEAKER_02]: gambling and throwing the World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he had nothing to it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a lot of belongings.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he's the guy that broke down and confessed.
[SPEAKER_02]: So there you go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gandal must have known something was coming.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was in.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was betweener for the gamblers and the players.
[SPEAKER_02]: They paid him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He paid off the rest of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: But you see, they got jipped on money.
[SPEAKER_02]: For instance, they didn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dick Curry won two games of the World Series with the rest of them trying to throw it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the gamblers were doubling their bets every day because it was a cinch.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Dick knocked them off.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they lost a bunch of dough there, and they had to rebuild.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they didn't have as much money to pay off with, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Dickie Kerr.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's how he won two games with that bunch.
[SPEAKER_02]: The shortstop third baseman and the first baseman, two outfielders going against him.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was Joe Jackson like?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a nice, quiet fellow.
[SPEAKER_02]: He never had much to say.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, he was kind of a dummy when he came up.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the reason they called him Chewbacca Joe.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used to play down on the last pair of footers and all that.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he was a nice guy to talk to.
[SPEAKER_02]: He never did talk much and all that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He spoke with his bat.
[SPEAKER_02]: But, hell, he hit .370 in the World Series, and they're trying to throw it.
[SPEAKER_01]: They say, though, he made a couple of his throws and might have been a little off target.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, maybe so.
[SPEAKER_02]: You can't tell on throws, because throws can happen that way.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or a pitcher might have to get one down the middle, see, instead of hitting the corner.
[SPEAKER_02]: Those things, you can't swear that they did it intentionally, because those things happen every day.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you first hear of this thing in the last week of season?
[SPEAKER_01]: You or the rest of the team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it in the newspapers?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they'd just broken the newspapers then, see, when it happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did those guys come to the club outside?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I hadn't seen them or ever.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you went running the lineup then for Jackson?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, let's see.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think I played right field that last series or so.
[SPEAKER_02]: But the next year after that, I worked in the left field.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some way to burn.
[SPEAKER_02]: In college, I pitched and played first base most of the time and hit fourth.
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched three years in college, never lost a college game.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you win?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: We wasn't playing about 50 games like we're playing now.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was playing 25, something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you like Kid Gleason?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he stay much longer after that?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know how many years he stayed, but I'm trying to see who...
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know whether Eddie Collins took his place.
[SPEAKER_02]: Eddie, of course, managed it for a year or two or three, but I don't know whether he left the police, because Shaw was in there for a year or two, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he had a manager a year almost.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I mean, he was in there for a year or two, and then there were some changes in there, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: And then, oh yeah, they had Frank Chance that was supposed to be in there, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: and take it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he got sick.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he reported there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wasn't in spring training.
[SPEAKER_02]: He reported there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And a little later on, he died.
[SPEAKER_02]: Johnny Evers, the old Tinkerster Evers of Chance, was his assistant, a coach.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they turned it over to Evers to run that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was 1924.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he managed to the rest of that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he didn't stay any longer than that one year.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I think Collins might have had it after that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I believe he did.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd have to look up.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't remember which.
[SPEAKER_02]: And even Lena Blackburn had it for the year.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was the last guy that played for it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I was traded to Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I saw you play at Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where did you go to spring training then in 21?
[SPEAKER_02]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_02]: In 21, I think we went to Walsh Hatch in Texas.
[SPEAKER_02]: I bought a house, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Paul Richards' house.
[SPEAKER_02]: Paul Richards' hometown.
[SPEAKER_02]: We would like to go up there, but our tour doesn't take us in that part of the state.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're heading out west.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you know Sam West?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a lover.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, you think he'd mind being interviewed?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know how healthy he is.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's had some trouble, but I don't know what it was, whether it's heart or something else.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know, but I don't...
[SPEAKER_02]: It's just somebody from out there that I knew that might know him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said something about it very long ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's probably been a year.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's been a year since his name was even mentioned.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used to have an interest in the sporting good business, but I think he sold out that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what he's doing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I grew up in Cleveland, of course.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was an Indian fan from way back, and it seemed like West was always beating Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: He could run and go get that ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they put you in left field then in 21?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I worked in left field.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, 285, pretty good year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's it.
[SPEAKER_02]: RBI is not bad for first year, 81.
[SPEAKER_02]: 82.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I mean, that isn't compared to today's stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had a lot of doubles.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm a double man.
[SPEAKER_02]: One year I got 44 or 5, if you notice, and 24, I believe.
[SPEAKER_02]: 26.
[SPEAKER_02]: 26, I believe.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that held a White Sox record up until about five or six years ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: And some nigger playing right field in 161 games hit about 47 or 8.
[SPEAKER_02]: I forgot who it was now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Al Smith?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't tell you, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had 300 lifetime doubles.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: When you're playing in a big park like White Sox, 352 both ways, and 400 and something in the center, and the crosswind messing you up, you had to cut down.
[SPEAKER_02]: I used to hit a lot of long flies, and then I cut down and start getting line drives, and that's where I hit doubles.
[SPEAKER_01]: I noticed when you went over to Cleveland, your home run output went up a lot.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you know, the right field fence there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you think you'd have been more of a home run hitter in a small park like that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you go for home runs at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't have to go for home runs in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: You could still do it the same way.
[SPEAKER_02]: And if you got a hold of it and got it high enough, you'd fall over that fence, see, in Old League Park.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a great old ballpark.
[SPEAKER_02]: God, with old Speaker and George Byrne, they'd get 50-something doubles in that park.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: George Byrne led the record for a while, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he hit a million doubles.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, remember Clyde Krause?
[SPEAKER_02]: Buck Krause?
[SPEAKER_02]: Catcher?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, the catcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's from Muncie, Indiana.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, there's been a whole evening with him one night.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's in bad health.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's gone downhill.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: This was in the fall of 75, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, five.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd heard something that he'd kind of gone sickly.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had some story to tell.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't like Eric Rabner.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, and I didn't either.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the reason I was traded.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: What was the story there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they wanted to cut me $2,500 one year, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the year they traded me.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, the year before, I had some... Yeah, but I mean, I didn't play quite as many games.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had some trench mouth trouble, and my gums and everything was bleeding, and I had to lay off some, and... And to show you what kind of guy he was,
[SPEAKER_02]: We always played the Cubs and City Series in the fall.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they didn't play me the last several weeks of the season.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now when I got to the damn City Series, they put me in to play against the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_02]: That showed up something to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: They wanted to win those games.
[SPEAKER_02]: They figured I was the best man to have in there, and they wouldn't play me the last part of the season.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you say they now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Grabner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he's the business manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's the brains.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's running that thing, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Donnie Bush, is he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think Lena Blackburn had a club then.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I know he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Grabner really dictated the field manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: Let me just show you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, here's something that you've never heard of, probably.
[SPEAKER_02]: If it happened today, they ain't going to tell him what the hell to do.
[SPEAKER_02]: But in that 24 year, I hit .352, didn't I?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_02]: All right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I didn't get, see, I didn't get, uh, I didn't get a raise next year, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, the day before I didn't get a raise or nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: And, uh, I went up to see Mr. Dravener and thought maybe he'd give me a little bonus, 500, for having a good year, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of them do that, some don't.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I thought at least I'd just kill 300 or 500 one day.
[SPEAKER_02]: And so I said, well, when you get home, you write Mr. Comischke a letter.
[SPEAKER_02]: I met Mr. Mistry in bad health and never was there half the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nobody ever met him, the player.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I did that.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I got a letter back, signed from Mr. Mistry, but that grabbed me a heap of imitated signature.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I'm not pretty sure about this statement I'm going to give you.
[SPEAKER_02]: I figure he did it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, during all my years in baseball, I never heard of a player refunding any money when he had a bad year.
[SPEAKER_02]: So why should I give you any extra money for having a good year?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what they wrote me.
[SPEAKER_02]: present time.
[SPEAKER_02]: They print it all in all the papers.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, they have it in all the papers, everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, one of the reasons for the scandal, of course, is that Comiskey Paces will sell it.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the reason they thought it was some easy money for the stars.
[SPEAKER_01]: Except Eddie Collins.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Eddie got his because he came from Connie Mack, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: And he got his set.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Jackson, I think Jackson
[SPEAKER_02]: was around $9,000 or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Buck Weaver, $7,500.
[SPEAKER_02]: Reesburg, a shortstop.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, he's only been there a couple of years, but he's outstanding.
[SPEAKER_02]: $3,600.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a side cover, $10,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the pitcher, well, he'd been a 20-game winner.
[SPEAKER_02]: And some of the other pitchers, $5,000 or $6,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't know what the other clubs.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've got to know what's playing in the league.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't know how to compare, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: The other guy is Reesburg.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was no good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tough competitor though?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was good there, but he was one of the hoodlum types of Californians.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gantle like that?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I didn't know Gantle.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Weaver seemed like a pretty nice chap.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got a kick out of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He tried to get reinstated a couple of times.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, yeah, I used to see him occasionally.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used to work at the neutral windows at the White Sox at the racetracks in Chicago for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: We'd have a rainy day, we'd go out to the track, see, and I'd see him at the window once in a while and talk to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: That seems to me like people like Weaver or maybe Jackson were rather roughly treated.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, see, Jackson, the way that trouble is, they got Weaver in on it, and Jackson, anything that Weaver said, Jackson would do.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was too dumb to be a leader, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So he sucked in some of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: They even got the...
[SPEAKER_02]: Just you tell the infielder.
[SPEAKER_02]: McMullin.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a friend of Risberg's.
[SPEAKER_02]: They were buddies.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't play.
[SPEAKER_02]: Risberg said, you got to let him in.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the way I understand it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I read about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: There must have been a lot of tension in the team that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess it was, but it might have been.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was internal.
[SPEAKER_02]: You never heard them talk, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Those players involved a lot have been together and talking.
[SPEAKER_02]: You never heard any communication between the rest of the players, never mentioned, because the club was up there, right at the top, last, and they blew it, and Cleveland does it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Cleveland got his first kind of snatching play.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was there any feeling against Eddie Collins because he got so much more money than anybody else?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't even know what he got.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, he's a smart man.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a graduate of Columbia, and he knew his business.
[SPEAKER_02]: he probably wouldn't have come over there without a term contract and a salary.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I knew they had to give it to him, because he was a great ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet Ben Johnson?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: I made quite a study of Ben Johnson's life.
[SPEAKER_02]: He went to Marietta College, where I teach, and gave him some money, and the field I was named after him now.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said I'd written some stuff on Ben, and I can't find many people to do him, though, that were really.
[SPEAKER_02]: If it came to ballgames, I don't know about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He and Comiskey were very close earlier.
[SPEAKER_02]: Until, and then they split.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what about.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he would go out the White Sox part because it's Comiskey's part.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was his league.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything exciting happen in those first couple of years of the White Sox?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any big days already?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't recall any.
[SPEAKER_01]: Five or five or six?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I'd have to look.
[SPEAKER_02]: Look, I don't even have any records to know myself.
[SPEAKER_02]: Naturally, you're going to have a few good days.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're going to have some bad days.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then again, you might have certain pitchers you do well against.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of them you don't.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sometimes you do well against the good pitchers and not against the others.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Walter Johnson?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was still pitching sometimes.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was still pretty fast.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I'd say he struck out 13 of them one day in the daytime.
[SPEAKER_02]: He must have been throwing pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was it easier against right-handers overall for you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I was a left-hand hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: That old rule applies.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anybody, right-hander, left-hander, always.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because you don't see a left-hander every day.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's got a different angle on him.
[SPEAKER_02]: But it didn't matter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Norman Johnson's pitching, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: It didn't matter.
[SPEAKER_02]: It didn't matter.
[SPEAKER_02]: There, he was throwing pretty hard.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, the one just as bad as him was Grove.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was.
[SPEAKER_02]: That guy was faster than Johnson.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or maybe Johnson.
[SPEAKER_02]: Johnson was a little bit over the hill.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was on the down side of some men.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have any favorites out there in the pitcher's box?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Certain pitchers you might get a little better than others.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about that George Yuley?
[SPEAKER_02]: I used to have good luck against George.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I've interviewed him.
[SPEAKER_02]: When he, before I got over Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could, if I hit it on the handle, it'd go safe, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, and then if I hit it good.
[SPEAKER_02]: In some way, I'd get on with some type of hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: It might not be a good one, but it'd swing hard and hit easy.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I could have pretty good luck.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd have to laugh at him sometimes, things that happened to me against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I talked to him about pitching to Ruth, and he says, well, the babe never gave you much trouble.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where did you get this nickname, Jockey?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, see, well, Eddie Collins used to be saying, well, certain guys we knew.
[SPEAKER_02]: We used to give Ruth a lot of time in Chicago and get in practice, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: We'd holler at him from our fence and go like a monkey hanging down.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we'd call him the big monkey, see, and holler at him like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we never, see, we was playing.
[SPEAKER_02]: We wasn't riding anybody during the game.
[SPEAKER_02]: This was all just kidding somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was more kidding than it was riding, not making money.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sometimes we'd have to be abiding at home, and the visiting team would have to come by our abode in case we'd get to the other side of the bench.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you'd hear something from one of the players say, did so-and-so come by asking about this?
[SPEAKER_02]: Something happened to him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I'd have to come by and get in touch with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: There wasn't a thing I heard about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they'd say, where in the hell did you get that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, ain't no one in St. Maunten, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ribbed me.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's all in good fun, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nothing against you.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, you're not that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Bill, I'm playing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wasn't hollering nobody, doing no games.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was just jockeying between somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did anybody particularly give you the label?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know where in the hell it came from.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was your first name a family name?
[SPEAKER_02]: It's kind of an unusual name.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it's... Depp Graves used to be the governor of Alabama over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: So it's several of them different.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of them got a last name.
[SPEAKER_02]: Doc could be about seeing some of those.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they call you Bibb and Tucker?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, some of them did, just the kids.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, how'd you hear about your trade to Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I just, it was in the spring.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was after Christmas before they rewired me.
[SPEAKER_02]: They rewired me, told me I'd been traded to Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: Grabbed me and signed a commission.
[SPEAKER_02]: because Comiskey would spend most of the summers up in Wisconsin, the summer home on where I lived.
[SPEAKER_02]: So then I got contact, and Cleveland contacted me after that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sent me a contract, and they sent me a contract I had without the cut, so I saved $2,500 there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then I went over and had a pretty good year farm, and he gave me $1,000 extra at the end of the season.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not to like Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was that, Barnard?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, that was Billy Evans.
[SPEAKER_02]: Billy Evans and Peckinpah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Peck had played with Chicago a year or so before he went over to Manhattan.
[SPEAKER_02]: I always liked Peck.
[SPEAKER_02]: We were good friends.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I had a couple of real nice interviews with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He lived in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: He died just there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he just died shortly after getting an A or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you...
[SPEAKER_01]: view of Peckinpah as a manager?
[SPEAKER_02]: He's great.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a great guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I knew him before I went over.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, OK.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's got not excitable type of guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Smooth going, not a holler guy, not a cozy guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he maybe too easy on some of the players, you think?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Depends on the type of player.
[SPEAKER_02]: I like him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd like to play for him forever.
[SPEAKER_02]: I played hard for him, did well.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd like to see him win.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's farm.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know anybody there that
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't recall anyone that he should have been on and he wasn't on or nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I knew most of them, and I know most of them were young then.
[SPEAKER_02]: They say, one story I heard, that like Eddie Morgan did a lot of drinking.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: They do it now.
[SPEAKER_02]: He might have done that, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he didn't do it regularly, but he loved to go out to a party or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he's been doing that since he went to college.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you know him from way back?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I know him until I ran up here in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was there when I first got here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Year he hit .350 or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, with all those home runs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he hit them over the right field fence right-handed.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He got an Elgin watch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember those Elgin watches?
[SPEAKER_01]: They sponsored the broadcast.
[SPEAKER_01]: We used to cheer for other Elgin ones.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then they sent me over to Toledo to manage it one year, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: In 32, I was over in Toledo managing for Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, were you through, though, in the big time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, yeah, they offered me my release or take that managing job.
[SPEAKER_02]: You did 304 in 1931.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, but I don't know why, but they probably had some young guys.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Joe Vosnick was coming up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they had Joe Vosnick coming up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gene Jamieson was washed up, and they had some other new players coming, and they offered me that job over there, or I'd give me a release, and I took the job managing.
[SPEAKER_02]: You played, then?
[SPEAKER_02]: I played and managed out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then they gave it up because during the Depression, we finished third, I believe, and lost a lot of money over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: It wasn't growing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Toledo was broke.
[SPEAKER_02]: All the banks were closed.
[SPEAKER_02]: All the factories were closed.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was in 1932.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right in the Depression.
[SPEAKER_02]: So then they took me back to Cleveland and I was a coach over there for a year, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Most of that year, until they let Peg go and brought in Walter Johnson.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then he brought in
[SPEAKER_02]: his own coaches, and that made me free.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, then Eddie Collins put me on scouting the rest of that summer, and then next year I was coaching for Eddie Collins' bunch in Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: Eddie didn't tell the manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bucky Harris was the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you scouting for him at the Red Sox?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, after he got in touch with me, I did some work for him down in this area after I left Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then the next spring,
[SPEAKER_02]: I was going to do that again, but then they got me to go down to the spring training camp with them to work with them as a coach.
[SPEAKER_02]: They kept me on all year as a coach.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dr. Harris was the manager that year in Boston.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then they made that trade with Washington, got Joe Cronin, that killed Harris and killed me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He brought Al Shack over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went on the road scouting then until I came over here coaching in 1940.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I scouted for Red Sox until I came here, and I coached here 25 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't play any more ball then, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I didn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: After I started here, I didn't mess with anybody.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wouldn't even scout for nobody, wouldn't do nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd just wait.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, how'd you get out of the Empire State?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: You mean up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: In the Big Three League?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, there were a lot of pop-ups, some of them, maybe because we were on occasion.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, I've never been chased by things that bother much.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think they do a pretty good job.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we had some, I thought, just better than others, like it always is when you've got a bunch of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: But we had some pretty good old umpires, old Tommy Connelly, Billy Evans, Dick Nallen,
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill Dineen, McGowan, Bill LeBrand, Fred Ormsby.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know, that's some of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know if that's all of them or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: Guthrie was quite a... Well, yeah, Guthrie was in there for a few years.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was quite a colorful figure, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: This or that, Guthrie.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's no evens, he says.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's either this or that.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's no evens.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, he was deep from Chicago.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used to be a plumber.
[SPEAKER_02]: That old cap around and hoodlum type, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got an umpire.
[SPEAKER_02]: Only umpire in the minor, isn't that it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you actually never played any minor league ball at all, except for Toledo that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Except for Toledo that year, I managed that play.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had some of the Cleveland players, Odell Hale, Linfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was Trotsky with them then?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, Nickerbocker.
[SPEAKER_02]: Trotsky was in the three-eye league before that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's correct.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then I had Monty Pearson.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a pretty good team.
[SPEAKER_02]: And some other older ones.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill Sweeney that used to play first for the Red Sox, he was first baseman.
[SPEAKER_02]: Butch Henline and Aldo Varmer were the catchers, the old catchers.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had Bev Bean and Craig Head.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bev Bean.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's up here in Comanche.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he lives in North Texas.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had he and Craig Head and Ronnie Pearson.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they were good.
[SPEAKER_02]: As far as too good, he ended up being basketball coach at Southern Cal out there, assistant athletic director of me.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we started out bad.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then they sent me some better players over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then we started going pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Minneapolis won it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tony Bush won it that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think we finished third.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you like managing?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was playing then.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had some pretty good players.
[SPEAKER_02]: You knew it.
[SPEAKER_02]: It wasn't too bad.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you're managing for a big league club.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was managing over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't know how it'd be working for a single owner that didn't have the money to go get you the players.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, Evans would come over and see the game and see some of the players.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he was smart.
[SPEAKER_02]: He knew whether I had the material or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: And some of them don't know that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you know Earl Everill pretty well?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Earl.
[SPEAKER_02]: He broke in with me this evening.
[SPEAKER_02]: Been there and there for two or three years, and I was with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hit a home run his first time out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't have too good an arm, but he was throwing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think he should be in the Hall of Fame?
[SPEAKER_02]: He's in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know he is.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's going to be, one of the few.
[SPEAKER_02]: He is.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that guy out in Seattle promoted that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some guy out there that did a lot of riding, Steve Elliott, or somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: He promoted him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was one of my heroes.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a good boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I hope to see him.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're going out to the West Coast and up
[SPEAKER_02]: Up to Seattle.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, from Snohomish, right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bob Johnson was around there, too, so I thought maybe I could try to see him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who are some of the players on the White Sox team in those, in the 20s there?
[SPEAKER_01]: The infields, for example.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they found, well, at first, after they kicked this bunch out, they had to make a deal to get some help in the infield.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they went to Salt Lake City.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Eddie Mulligan, he used to tread liver.
[SPEAKER_02]: the Coast League or the California State League.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Ernie Johnson, the shortstop there, both came from Salt Lake City.
[SPEAKER_02]: Earl Shealy, first baseman from Salt Lake City.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Sloppy Thurston, the pitcher, from Salt Lake City.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they got that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Collin was still there to play second.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that was the end for him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then Johnny Moskow was over in the Association of Milwaukee the year before, and he came up
[SPEAKER_02]: put him in center, and I played left, and they traded for Harry Hooper, and Harry Hooper was in right.
[SPEAKER_02]: They got him in Boston.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that's about what we started with.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we had Teddy Lyons.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, Ted wasn't there right then.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't see him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was 23, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, 23.
[SPEAKER_02]: But we lost those three starters.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Kerr show?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you see, Kerr had contract trouble there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He jumped the club, went over there to Oregon, Wisconsin, or one of those, and played semi-pro over there, and got better money than he did with the Whites.
[SPEAKER_02]: So then later, they got Al Thomas and Baltimore to pitch up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Red Faber was still there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Faber, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Faber and D.P.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kerr were still there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Dror Wilkerson was a relief pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they got somebody else, but they wasn't too hot.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't finish up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not when you lose those kind of players.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, we were in 2nd Division all the years out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: The only time I was in 1st Division was the year Cleveland finished 3rd.
[SPEAKER_02]: You remember the—were you around when Mossel tried to do something?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was training camp with him on Shreveport.
[SPEAKER_02]: Uri Ota.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did he do?
[SPEAKER_02]: He just cut himself?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was—yes, he was Haywire.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a razor blade and tried to cut himself and didn't know how to kill himself.
[SPEAKER_02]: They tied him in a bathroom up there and took him to the hospital and sewed him up and he didn't, he didn't utter anything, nothing to kill himself.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a funny guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Great outfielder and good hustler and good base fielder.
[SPEAKER_02]: Fair leadoff man, but he, I've seen him run up to the left field fence and left center and ball just go over and fall in the bleachers and says, oh, I got it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'll run it, but he'll chance to catch it too.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've seen him instead of ducking on a fly ball in the sun, he'd let it hit him on the face or somewhere, and it wouldn't even get out of the way.
[SPEAKER_02]: And if he said he got it, you better let him have it, because I've played left field and I've had it run out of the way a lot of times, but if he caught a cross there, you better let him have it, he'll run over you.
[SPEAKER_02]: In fact, I used to tell a story at Chicago, which wasn't true, about me and Mossler.
[SPEAKER_02]: So Mossler caught a foul ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Centerfield passed me and left me.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't true, though.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know no Centerfield, George.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just to illustrate, though, the way he did tell the crowd.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's what it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was on me and on him, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Alex Metzler?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, old Alex.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's in California.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's still living there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Let's see, I'm not sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: I take the sporting ones.
[SPEAKER_02]: I still take them, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I look at obituaries all the time to see who's still going.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I played with him a year or two in Chicago before I was traded.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he's a good hustler, good lead-off man.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ted Lyons used to, what'd we say about him when he run down to first place?
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, he used to dig like him, and he usually did.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's going to be out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said the muscle saved him a lot of hits and runs by his feeling.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, feeling, he did.
[SPEAKER_02]: He could go get that ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's good arm, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, his arm is just fair.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's the center field, I'd say.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he could go get that ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd run and he'd catch it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he'd save you a lot.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a big area in White Sox, because it's over 400 feet and 350 down the line.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've got a lot of area.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember a Ted Lyons no-hitter?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Charlie Robinson have a no-hitter there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was against Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was a perfect game, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Perfect game, and they had Ty Cobb and Bob Veech and some of those pretty good ballplayers on there, and Cobb was out there calling to look at the ball and everything else on him, trying to figure he was cheating or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: Trying to unnerve him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Unnerve him, and he never did do it, and he had no run.
[SPEAKER_02]: My name's not in that lineup, because I was sick or hurt that day, and I didn't play that one day in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: So when you see the lineup, I'm not in it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you see the game?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was there on the bench, but I was either something's mattered with me or I'd have been there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there a lot of tension building up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I can't recall.
[SPEAKER_02]: All I know, of course, against Detroit, you're looking for a guy to unload any minute, because they had some good hitters.
[SPEAKER_02]: Cobb.
[SPEAKER_02]: Cobb, he could steal first base, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: want one or do something.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you know Ty very well?
[SPEAKER_02]: I used to talk to him some.
[SPEAKER_02]: I tried to talk to him some, but he...
[SPEAKER_02]: I liked to talk to him, make him look smart, ask him about kittens or things like that, see, get his opinion.
[SPEAKER_02]: He liked to give that, see, which he gave me some good ones, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: But that's the one way to get along with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He could be pretty tough, couldn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He liked to talk stock market and all that stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: He made a million off of General Motors and Coca-Cola.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's from Georgia, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: And he played in Detroit, the headquarter of General Motors.
[SPEAKER_02]: The trouble is he had a lot of money and no friends.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't too successful a manager, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he didn't know how to handle people.
[SPEAKER_02]: He couldn't handle players.
[SPEAKER_01]: I suppose when you're that good a player, too, it's kind of hard to- Well, I'd expect him to be as good as you are, not like- A horse be.
[SPEAKER_02]: He would come in from center field with a pitcher's box or way in there and talk to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know how you managed from center field.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said he thought he could.
[SPEAKER_02]: Speaker did it, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Speaker did, but he didn't do that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was pretty lucky in Big Lake Bowl.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got to travel a lot, and it never cost me any money.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't know these things, though, because that trip I was telling you about the reason I didn't go, the thorn starving trip promoted by Herbie Hunter, was after the World Series in 1922, I believe it was, between the Giants and the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we had Wade Hoyt, Herb Panik, Freddie Hoffman, Joe Bush,
[SPEAKER_02]: George Kelly, Casey Stengel, Irish Musial.
[SPEAKER_02]: All had been in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: And had Amos Trunk and myself in the White Sox, a couple of Cleveland guys, Luke Sewell and Stevenson, Riggs.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'd just been up there a year or two, a couple of years.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Bird Griffith from Brooklyn, Doc LeVant from the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_02]: And let's see here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got just about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And their wives, some of their wives, we had 26 in a party.
[SPEAKER_02]: George Moriarty was on it, the big, big umpire.
[SPEAKER_02]: Buck O'Neill from New York Sun.
[SPEAKER_02]: 26 in a party.
[SPEAKER_02]: We sailed out of Vancouver October the 19th and got back to Frisco February the 1st of next spring.
[SPEAKER_02]: This is to Japan, right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, in Japan is when it was first stopped.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tokyo, and then Kobe, and stayed in Japan and played a lot.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then went up and played a game in Seoul, Korea.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we caught a train, not to play, but we had to go up to Mugden, Manchuria, to change on the Chinese railroad to go into Peking, China.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we didn't play there, it was a sightseeing trip.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then we went from there to Shanghai, and we played in Shanghai.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had some kind of wagon out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And from there we went to the Philippines for about a week, plain army and everything else.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then we were all by boat, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: There wasn't any goddamn airplanes.
[SPEAKER_02]: It took us 11 days by boat to get there from Vancouver.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play in Japan, the college teams?
[SPEAKER_01]: Colleges and graduate teams.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you have to try the college, they had some, of course.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I had some out around Kobe, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: But in China, you just had four?
[SPEAKER_02]: China, we just played one in Korea.
[SPEAKER_02]: So there's a ragnot.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a team there.
[SPEAKER_02]: A ragnot?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, a ragnot means not a good team.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, like a pickup team.
[SPEAKER_02]: But we just made that side trip around to get to Shanghai, stay on the train.
[SPEAKER_02]: We was in Peking three or four days.
[SPEAKER_02]: In those days, the United States was working with China because we had a legation there in Peking, and they had a company of Marines there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And at Ten-Cin, they had a division of soldiers in those days.
[SPEAKER_02]: So those Marines showed us all around, took us out to the Great Wall, and showed us there and about shopping, had lunch over there with them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of us did.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they showed us all around in China.
[SPEAKER_02]: We was at the Peking Hotel, and it's still there.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we caught the train down to Shanghai and was there two or three days, and then caught the boat down there to Manila.
[SPEAKER_02]: Governor General Wood was the Governor General.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when he was the head man there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had army teams and everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, that's all we played.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it was hot.
[SPEAKER_02]: You see, we left Shanghai, they was wearing top coats.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right when they passed the date line, and God, man, you landed down there below the international date line, it was hot.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just like in Texas.
[SPEAKER_02]: They was wearing whites, you know, but they're white.
[SPEAKER_02]: We liked to dive after the first game or two we played, and that heat.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we made port calls to Hong Kong and back around to Yokohama.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then we took nine days to Honolulu, 10 days to Waukee Beach.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we played teams there, Army and everything else.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then we took the boat and landed in Frisco.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then two years later, in 24, the New York Giants and the White Sox, Comiskey and McGraw, took both teams to Europe.
[SPEAKER_02]: We played in England, Ireland, and France.
[SPEAKER_02]: Same teams.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had the whole team, not a small team.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had the whole team of White Sox Giants.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was another trip.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's another trip two years later.
[SPEAKER_02]: I say I got all this out of the game.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's great.
[SPEAKER_02]: Free.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we had, White Sox had to pick up a few players, but some of the others couldn't go.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got Sammy Rice and Val Pacinic from the Washington team.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had Dave Van Cross.
[SPEAKER_01]: How were you picked in 22?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any particular reason?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, no, I guess because we could go.
[SPEAKER_02]: We were single and, you know, could get away.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anybody who was specifically invited?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Herbie Hunter.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know why he come to pick on me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I'll tell you why.
[SPEAKER_02]: Charlie Robertson.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it was Charlie Robertson.
[SPEAKER_02]: Charlie Robertson and Herbie Hunter, and one other man, made a trip over to Japan a year or so before the kind of coaching clinic.
[SPEAKER_02]: They invited them over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's what got it started.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, Hunter got to build up this trip.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I think Robertson recommended us, because he used to be
[SPEAKER_02]: on the White Sox in Charlottesville.
[SPEAKER_02]: I imagine it very much.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anyhow, he approached us about if we wanted to go or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who put the word in, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: But Luke and Stevie wasn't married either, so they were all single guys.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it's easier to get those guys to go than you could married guys.
[SPEAKER_02]: But some of them had children.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'd have to pay their own expenses.
[SPEAKER_02]: But hey, we'd gone three months and a half.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a long time.
[SPEAKER_02]: But over the other, we'd only gone about six weeks.
[SPEAKER_02]: We left Montreal.
[SPEAKER_02]: And landed in Liverpool, and we played in Liverpool and Birmingham.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then went over to Dublin, Ireland and played a game.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we moved into London.
[SPEAKER_02]: We played before the King and Queen in England.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we was all lined up and introduced to him individually.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the Prince of Wales, the one that married the American woman, he was young then.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came right in behind him, the Duke of York, and introduced us all right to him, both lines.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, and the Queen was up in the stands, waving the flag.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you play cricket fields?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, it was soccer fields, a short center field.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a—Houns Lobert, you know who he is?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was McGraw's assistant.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd go out and lay out the diamonds, or help lay them out for the field, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: And they'd be laid out that way.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did the British think of that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: They gave me a write-up in one of the London papers.
[SPEAKER_02]: One of the guys interviewed me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we went over to Paris and played a game in Paris over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, we'd have gone by there because baseball wasn't nothing in Paris.
[SPEAKER_02]: France, they didn't have nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now we sailed and came back to New York on the Leviathan.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we hit a storm and had to stand by for a day as big as that ship was.
[SPEAKER_02]: A day late getting into New York.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I got more of that out of baseball than other people did.
[SPEAKER_01]: You weren't married then?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get married later on?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I've never been married.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: My sister's never been married.
[SPEAKER_02]: So then I've been here so long, you know, I've kind of forgotten pro-baseball because I've been tied up in college so long.
[SPEAKER_01]: You coached from 1940 to 75, then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, no, not 75.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was 68.
[SPEAKER_02]: 25 years.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1940.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1940 is when I started here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Mr.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dish got sick, and I asked who he wanted.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your old coach, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: My old coach, and he got well.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I asked him who he wanted to take his place, and he said me, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So I took it over, and I stayed until 1967.
[SPEAKER_02]: 25 years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Won 20 championships, and finished second three times.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of these?
[SPEAKER_02]: 25.
[SPEAKER_02]: Which conference?
[SPEAKER_02]: Southwest Conference.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you get to the World Series?
[SPEAKER_02]: Won it twice.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: In Omaha.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1949 and 50.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1949 in Wichita and 50 in first year in Omaha.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I finished second and third up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was up there seven or eight times, but I won it twice in a row, two years in a row.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's great.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did any of your boys make it to the big time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, there's one played with Cleveland, Max Alvis.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was one of the boys.
[SPEAKER_02]: He left when he was a sophomore.
[SPEAKER_02]: He never quite... Muriel Wall.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was at the Red Sox for a little while.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's triple-A mostly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about when you're...
[SPEAKER_01]: Going out to the field for a game and a clubhouse meeting, do you have these all the time or before a game?
[SPEAKER_02]: You mean where?
[SPEAKER_02]: College or A&R?
[SPEAKER_01]: In the club, yeah, in the big time.
[SPEAKER_02]: We used to only have meetings when we opened the season and playing the club the first time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because that's a new player.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we have some new pitchers and stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they'd go over the lineup and tell you about who did this or who did that, or if anybody played against one of them in the minors, knew something about them.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's usually the goal of them, see, the first trip around.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, occasionally I'd call something to go over something or do something.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wouldn't say we had a whole lot of meetings.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd like to do.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I don't know whether I have a lot now.
[SPEAKER_01]: It doesn't look like it sometimes.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't.
[SPEAKER_02]: Most of them know how to play.
[SPEAKER_02]: Unless you have certain stuff you want to put over, signs or disciplinary stuff you want to talk over that they've got to cut out or somebody had done it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there tough discipline in the White Sox in the 20s?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I didn't have any discipline.
[SPEAKER_02]: No?
[SPEAKER_01]: What were the rules, though?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, of course, I guess you had them if you were doing it at midnight, most of them do.
[SPEAKER_02]: I remember Peckinpah, he told you to be in by midnight.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, I used to play, and I used to go out with these gals and friends.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, if you're going to do any good, you're going to do it by midnight.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you don't, you might as well come on home.
[SPEAKER_02]: You passed right by the ballpark over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: The university?
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, you wouldn't know it because you're looking, but you know when you came on in to the hospital morning, the big round dome on the left?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's our new activity center, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Basketball.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they had the Lawrence Welk show in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they had some, just finished some tennis stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: These pro tennis came in for the tournament last night.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they had a lot of other big league stuff in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: couldn't get together, but they were going to have Barnard and Bailey in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: That belongs to them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just past that, on the right, you're a little low there coming.
[SPEAKER_02]: You couldn't see it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just up there about two or three blocks on the right, over a block, was our new ballpark.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got a $2.5 million college baseball field.
[SPEAKER_02]: Past the turf, seats 5,000 with aluminum chair seats in it, big league long benches.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you go up in your clubhouse, nice clubhouses, umpires' dressing rooms, concrete things with a hood out over it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Lights, $125,000 lights.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the name of the park is Dish Falk Field.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Isn't that nice?
[SPEAKER_02]: We're the best in the United States right now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nobody's got a park that good.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a college field, I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: It seats 5,000?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's not counting if you put bleachers down inside and add another.
[SPEAKER_02]: How big a schedule do they play over there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, last year he played about 51 games.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was limited to 25 when I was coaching.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then they opened the gate.
[SPEAKER_02]: They opened the gate on fall practice.
[SPEAKER_02]: I couldn't have fall practice.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then they let freshmen play.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never could play freshmen.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then what they did, then it's got two or three more teams in the conference now that wasn't in it when I left.
[SPEAKER_02]: Like Texas Tech out there, love it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Arkansas was too far away, and now they're at it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the University of Houston is in the conference house.
[SPEAKER_02]: They weren't at it before.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that adds some more teams.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they got 24 conference games.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then you're allowed so many days other than your conference games.
[SPEAKER_02]: And what this guy does, every time he has somebody in here to spring for a game, he plays a doubleheader.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't say how many games, just days.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he doubles every day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Are these seven innings, a couple of eight?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, sometimes, yeah, usually seven and nine.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sometimes they'll play more.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, if Minnesota comes down here, they'll play two seven-inning games, because they've been in the cold so long they haven't been outside.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they're not ready to play.
[SPEAKER_02]: The pitchers haven't pitched outside.
[SPEAKER_02]: So Dick Siebert brings them down here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who is the new coach, or your successor?
[SPEAKER_02]: Gustafson.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he played for me when he was in college.
[SPEAKER_02]: got his leg broke on a double play against University of Oklahoma when he had an exhibition game out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: But then he was coached in high school in San Antonio for a long time, had winning teams over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he's gone well there for six, seven years.
[SPEAKER_02]: He won the last two years, he hadn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: Another thing that messed up our place, too, the NCAA, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Their votes are run by small schools.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm a representative.
[SPEAKER_01]: All right.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know what you mean.
[SPEAKER_02]: You see, they make the rules.
[SPEAKER_02]: The big schools have to live on them.
[SPEAKER_02]: All right.
[SPEAKER_02]: They cut the scholarships.
[SPEAKER_02]: They said they wouldn't allow it.
[SPEAKER_02]: They cut scholarships down to 13 for baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: We'll always give them 20.
[SPEAKER_02]: Texas A&M, 20.
[SPEAKER_02]: So some of these other schools just have 5, or 6, or 10, or like SMU, or Rice, or maybe Texas Tech, TCU.
[SPEAKER_02]: And if it gives me a scholarship, of course, there wasn't as big an athletic program as we had.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't draw football like we'd pay for it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now they've cut us down to 13.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you're losing seven prospects there to bring in to keep your team going.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now you might bring in two or three, and if they're not stars, you're not strengthening your team much if you're rebuilding.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then maybe the scouts will come along and get some of your juniors.
[SPEAKER_02]: They can sign them after a junior year or 21 years of age, and they'll beat you there.
[SPEAKER_02]: So it's hard to build it back up when it gets down, because they went and passed that rule.
[SPEAKER_01]: How are your relations with the scouts?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have trouble with the scouts?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, because they got rules now.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, when I was coaching, they could sign them any time.
[SPEAKER_02]: I lost freshman and anything.
[SPEAKER_02]: You could do anything you wanted to.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, if the kid starts school, he's got to, at the end of the third year or 21 years of age, he's eligible.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, what these scouts might do, they might talk the kid in and go to junior college.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, that's a two-year school.
[SPEAKER_02]: He can be drafted any year in the junior college, his first or his second year, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Then he gets two years to look at him and sign him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or if he goes here, he's got to stay at least three, maybe four.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they sometimes they treat you that way, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: How do you do your recruiting?
[SPEAKER_01]: Where do you get contacts from former players?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, yeah, you keep up with former players and some other coaches.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they have the state championship playoff here.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're going to have it next week.
[SPEAKER_01]: On the?
[SPEAKER_02]: For baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: High school here.
[SPEAKER_01]: On their field?
[SPEAKER_02]: On our field.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'll have four 418s, that's top.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then they'll have four 318s.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, they haven't been having any lower than that, but I heard that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know whether they're going to do it this year or maybe next, but it has been those two.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's eight of the best.
[SPEAKER_02]: senior teams playing here.
[SPEAKER_02]: So of course, the coach gets to see him play here if he hasn't seen him, or maybe he's heard about him so he can see him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then he goes around in these playoffs before they get there and look at him, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: It says here your brother was Chet Falk.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he's still living.
[SPEAKER_02]: He lives out here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he playing a big time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was at the Browns for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: They signed him out of high school.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is he older?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he's younger than me.
[SPEAKER_02]: He signed out of high school with Brown.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then later, he was with Buffalo a year, and he was with Montreal a year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know, probably Dallas for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he hurt his arm in there quite quick.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I'll see you later.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he's a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you fare?
[SPEAKER_01]: as a fielder out there in my field.
[SPEAKER_02]: I did all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had one year, if you notice, I only made four errors in fielding.
[SPEAKER_02]: Four or five one year.
[SPEAKER_02]: If it gives you that error.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everything gives a feeling.
[SPEAKER_01]: Houston, the other encyclopedia was new, and I think they tried to streamline it, but it wasn't that good.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it's one year I only had about four errors.
[SPEAKER_01]: Assist, you racked up some assists.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I had a good year there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had about 24 assists one year from the left field.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's not the guy going from first to third like the right fielder.
[SPEAKER_02]: Would these be at second or at home or both?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd be everywhere.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd be throwing everywhere.
[SPEAKER_02]: A guy trying to go 2-0 on you, he might get it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He might be going 1st or 3rd.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe throw him out of the plate.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's just a total.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Babe Ruth wrote a book once.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, in Cahoots is his writer.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it's Christy Walsh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I think Christy.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in there, he talked about some outstanding plays.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he mentioned a catch that Johnny Mostel made and another that I made in Yankee Stadium, diving after a ball and hitting a cinder track and coming up with it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he thought were the best catches he's seen with outfielders.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ted Lyons told a story about how one year, Ruth picked him on his all-star team, picking all-American team every year.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Ted Lyons won his pitches.
[SPEAKER_01]: Next year, season began, the White Sox were in Yankee Stadium, and Ruth was out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ted, I guess, was down on the offbeat left, and Frank prayed before putting on his All-Star team.
[SPEAKER_02]: He probably didn't even know it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ruth was in the dugout.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was that guy?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Will Osweiler.
[SPEAKER_02]: Somebody else did, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Chris Madison was still living way back there, and he... Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: The Liberty magazine.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm a Liberty Magazine man.
[SPEAKER_02]: I used to be a sport magazine.
[SPEAKER_02]: I ain't kind of like Sports Illustrated.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a nice baseball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: All right.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Christie picked the All-American team for that one year.
[SPEAKER_02]: National American.
[SPEAKER_02]: He picked me in the All-American team one year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it was the year I hit .352. Who was the most viable player that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: 24.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd have to keep up with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Manny Manouche or Garland or one of those, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would seem like a pretty
[SPEAKER_01]: You should have been in the race today.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't hit home runs, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess you got to hit a lot of home runs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, well, I wasn't a home run hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: You hit them to all fields, did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, infield and outfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: You mean you bunted a lot?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: I allowed to hit any field.
[SPEAKER_02]: How do you do that?
[SPEAKER_02]: You just control that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I kind of copied Cobb a little bit.
[SPEAKER_02]: I spread my hands apart, chopping down instead of swinging for the long out.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, and I was hitting line drives.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hit one outside, you'd either hit it down the third baseline or right through there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ty always practiced trying to hit right through the middle.
[SPEAKER_02]: Past that pitcher for base hits, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Chop them fast.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you'd consciously try?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, if they're pitching you there, you'd hit it there, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: You wouldn't be trying to pull it out there and killing yourself like a lot of these guys do these days.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then again, you might get set with a man on first and try to pull it past that first baseman right sharp, so you send him a third, but they don't do that anymore.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they don't play hit and run much now.
[SPEAKER_02]: First and third, they're always hitting in double play.
[SPEAKER_02]: And all they have to do is start the man slapping on the ground.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've got a run and a man scoring position.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they don't do that.
[SPEAKER_02]: It hurts their batting average.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't get a hit for that.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they get a ribby.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I mean, they play on the hot TV right now.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know who it is, but they're playing.
[SPEAKER_01]: The bunting, did you do bunting?
[SPEAKER_02]: It was terrible there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was one of the better bunters.
[SPEAKER_02]: Peckinpah said, my best bunters are my best hitters.
[SPEAKER_02]: Last language, at least.
[SPEAKER_01]: I sometimes think that today, when they're sent up the bunk to sacrifice, they literally miss it so they can swing.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they can swing.
[SPEAKER_02]: The hell of it is that 200 hitters and they don't do them any good to swing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they might once in a while usually strike out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't get up on their bat, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Not even Sissler.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sissler is another guy I've talked to about hitting.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, he was a hell of a hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He only hit 400 a couple of times.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was talking to him, and he was scouting for somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Austin used to be in a Texas league here and a lower league, and he was scouting.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I happened to sit with him in the box, and we was talking about hitting.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he kind of thought like I did, or I thought like he did, but he varied according to the type of pitching.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, and that's stamina.
[SPEAKER_02]: Get a fair and certain distance to the plate and that, and do it on all guys, because pitchers got different movements of the ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sinkers out there are
[SPEAKER_02]: or a curved ball that breaks off like that, their throw is different.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you've got to move up a little bit or do certain things to combat that, don't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: You're going to be weak on that same pitch all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: But you don't see any of these guys moving around.
[SPEAKER_02]: And even Ted Williams says he had two strikes.
[SPEAKER_02]: He moves up on the bat a little bit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Control it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't strike out as much.
[SPEAKER_02]: You need to be sure it hits that ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I did the same thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, I was off the end anyhow with this, and I just didn't
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, I wasn't on the end, I was up about that much, but hands apart a little.
[SPEAKER_02]: And chops, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Hit line drive.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, you're doing some good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Red Ruffing told somebody that I was the hardest guy he ever had to strike out.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a pretty good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't strike out much, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not quite as good as Joey Sewell, but... Well, I did first, eighty-something, sixty, eighty.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sixty-nine the first year.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then it got down to twenty, didn't it, one year?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, eight.
[SPEAKER_02]: Eight one year?
[SPEAKER_01]: Because that was only eighty-two games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I mean...
[SPEAKER_01]: He played in the full schedule, it was in the twenties.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what I'm saying, that's pretty good, not like Joey.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's got a bat over there, I was in touch with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: You go over and talk to Joey?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he's got a bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: The part where he hits the ball, I've forgotten exactly what it's representing, but there's a mark on that bat where he always makes that kind of sound.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Joe just laid it right up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He really studied that matter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he didn't have a long stroke.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't swing out further than that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wasn't one of those guys who would throw your head out of gear.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe, meeting that ball, he wasn't a home run hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a single and double hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd be glad to see him get in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: But here you have a better lifetime value than he did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, yeah, but he played more games than I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: 314, he said.
[SPEAKER_02]: He played more than I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't care about the Hall of Fame and that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't mean nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pro ball, I've scared too much.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've kind of forgotten pro ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: I take the sport news and follow the old names I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I get a Christmas card, like old Willie Cam used to play.
[SPEAKER_02]: He lives out in Burlingame.
[SPEAKER_02]: He lives in Burlingame.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I get a crystal card for him, Teddy Lyons, a few of the guys still living.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Art the Great Shire?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know him?
[SPEAKER_02]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's from up in Waxahachie.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, that's where he is.
[SPEAKER_02]: He joined the White Sox when I was still there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Later, I was traded.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had all the trouble after I was gone.
[SPEAKER_02]: He is tough as he thought he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know how tough he was, but he chewed it back and drank.
[SPEAKER_02]: Art the Great.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that's about all my baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Sissel?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I knew Bill.
[SPEAKER_02]: But Smead was after me.
[SPEAKER_02]: They tell a story about Smead in Boston, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You've never been to Red Sox Park?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, back there, they fixed it now, but it used to have to go up that cliff in the back, way back there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They leveled it down, you know, just have a gradual slope.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had to run up that cliff, you see.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, Smead, he was having
[SPEAKER_02]: having trouble with that cliff, and they told him, well, that's what Cam told me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, well, you've got to learn to run up that place and then turn around and find the ball, see, judge the ball and catch it, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Don't try to go up and be looking, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he did that once, and Danford didn't work, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: So a little later on that same game, the wind changed, and he was carrying the ball back in a little bit, see, when it was coming down.
[SPEAKER_02]: He ran up that thing,
[SPEAKER_02]: Turn around to get it, the boat kind of faded out, and he stepped out and fell right flat on his belly down that hill, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So he came in, in the bench, and they saw that and everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you guys told me how to go up that hill, but you didn't tell me how to come down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hope to see Smead Jolly.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's many stories about him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's out there in Alameda, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've never seen him there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just catch what I see in the morning.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any, well, anything stand out in your career about crazy plays or exciting plays or big thrills?
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your biggest thrill?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I couldn't put my finger on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nothing happened to that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't think of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you like playing in Luke Park?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that a great left fielder's field?
[SPEAKER_02]: That field was tough on account of the sun.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's a bad son for you, there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a long field, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, and you had a long throw.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dick Porter played right from out here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Twitchy Dick.
[SPEAKER_02]: He died here right about then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Averill played center, Twitchy played there, and I played left.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then Vosnick came along.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you said on the phone yesterday, Joe Harzer wasn't with the club that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, no, I heard that Joe was with Connie Maxon, and I might have ran against Joe in the big leagues, as far as I know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a nice time with your mother.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's up in Sheboygan.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he lives up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He has a great home on Internemonial.
[SPEAKER_02]: Toland Bases, you had?
[SPEAKER_02]: That ain't Steel Bases.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did the White Sox put the runners on their own?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: As far as I know, maybe Collins would run on his own, somebody like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: When Cleason was running a team at college, he told me to do something, and Cleason said something.
[SPEAKER_02]: He gave you a sign to do what college said, and Cleason wouldn't say nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's all I know.
This is the right date here, your birth, January 27, 1899.
Right, I'm born on 60.
[SPEAKER_01]: 80, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Boy, that's great.
[SPEAKER_01]: What have you been doing since you retired then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I go out sometimes watching practice, see all the college baseball games in the spring.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's always something going around.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's a college this big with 40,000 students.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's always all the sports going on.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's always something.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then you have all your state runoffs right here, your state basketball tournament, see the champions.
[SPEAKER_02]: All your state track meets, and you have all that stuff going on if you want it.
[SPEAKER_02]: All of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: All that stuff going on here.
[SPEAKER_01]: You follow the football team much?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know the coaches real well.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't leave town anymore, but I see all the games here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, yeah, I know the coach.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was the president coach.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was here a long time before he went up where he was, Wyoming.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I knew him before he went.
[SPEAKER_02]: Freddie Akers, he's a country boy from over in Arkansas.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, nothing nuts you can think of to add to what we have so far?
[SPEAKER_01]: You had a great career up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm in the College Baseball Coaches Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm in the Texas Sports Writers Hall of Fame here in Texas.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they're going to build, like I told you before, build a big thing for that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Have all the pictures of all of them in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They came around and got a few pictures I had and anything I could give them, so they'll probably put that when they have them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess in the hall, if I have some stuff around the bottom or something to show, I guess they have them.
[SPEAKER_02]: They haven't started the building yet, but they're going to.
[SPEAKER_02]: They took all your pictures?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they took what I wanted to give away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have money?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I didn't have money.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you keep a scrapbook?
[SPEAKER_02]: Kids bring me...
[SPEAKER_02]: I get mobile mail.
[SPEAKER_02]: For Christ's sakes, they still send you postcards with your pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know where they get them, but you get them and then you just get blank cards.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah, I had a letter there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They sent me 30 cards to autograph.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're little square cards like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: And let's see, someplace.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had a Hall of Fame deal or some kind of thing over there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, anyhow, they was doing that right, and probably a lot of other old folks there, present too.
[SPEAKER_02]: And those who visit that Hall of Fame thing and that, they'll give them an autographed card.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, it's a souvenir.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they think of more rackets.
[SPEAKER_02]: They run you nuts.
[SPEAKER_02]: I get kids from California and all over.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then, you know, I'm on a bubble gum card, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they'll get some of those.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they'll send you those to autographs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Those are very valuable now.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they'll send you a bubble gum card.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used to collect them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have probably a couple of your cards back in the 30s.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'd like to take your picture, if I might.
[SPEAKER_01]: At the KOA campground in Fredericksburg, Texas, on the evening of the day after the Bibb-Falk interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would be Sunday night, June 4, 1978.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rita and I are here in a beautiful, practically deserted KOA campground in the rolling hills of South Central Texas, I guess it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: Looking around this campground, I see only about nine trailers, no tents.
[SPEAKER_01]: She says at the start of the hill country.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's just been a beautiful afternoon and evening, sunny and not too warm in the mid-80s probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: And from our tent site here, we get a panoramic view of the horizon to the north of us.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just a very lovely, grassy, tree-lined, uncongested site.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're very happy here.
[SPEAKER_01]: We wish we could stay here longer.
[SPEAKER_01]: After what happened in Austin yesterday, during the Bibfock interview, I might say,
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me go back and describe what happened there.
[SPEAKER_01]: First, let me check and see that I'm coming through.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm coming through.
[SPEAKER_01]: All right, this all began.
[SPEAKER_01]: When did it begin?
[SPEAKER_01]: I called Bibb Falk.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, it was Friday night I called him in our
[SPEAKER_01]: tent site there at KOA Austin, south of Austin, about six miles from the center of town, a very highly congested area with trailers all over the place.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, I think Rita just read this is the most, the largest KOA campground in the country.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that what you read?
No.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you read?
[SPEAKER_02]: I read that it's so tense.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, she read something else.
[SPEAKER_01]: She read the state capitol building, which we saw this morning, was the largest in the country.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that what you read?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, anyhow, something was the largest in the country, whatever it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it was a pretty big campground, even though it may not have been the biggest.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had a tiny corner there right next to the woodshed.
[SPEAKER_01]: A1, it was called.
[SPEAKER_01]: I called him from the office on Friday night.
[SPEAKER_01]: And right away, he said he'd gotten my card, my letter.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we began talking about where we could meet.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was tied up Saturday morning.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he had some time Saturday afternoon.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't have any room at his place, nothing there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so he was going to come out to my place.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he wondered where I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm living in a tent.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, what, a tent?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I thought the interview was dead then.
[SPEAKER_01]: He must have thought I was some hillbilly from West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I said, yeah, we're camping our way across the country.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I think we have electric power at our campsite.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if we had no place at his home, then if he could come out here, why, yes, that would be fine on a lovely June afternoon with the sun beaming down, nice and comfortable under the shaded trees there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I gave him the wrong place to cut off.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said Cannon Street, when it was Congress Street.
[SPEAKER_01]: As it turned out, that didn't matter very much.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he agreed.
[SPEAKER_01]: 2 o'clock, he'd come out to our campsite.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we'd have the interview there at our table, maybe.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd say, give me an hour, so then you'd have to leave.
[SPEAKER_01]: All right, so I was quite pleased he was willing to talk to me, although the idea he wouldn't let me come to his house, I was somewhat suspect about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Friday night started out very nicely.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then there began to be heard the little pitter patter of raindrops on our roof.
[SPEAKER_01]: And maybe over on Rita's side, a little bit of drip, drip, drip inside the roof.
[SPEAKER_01]: We hadn't waterproofed our roof too well, as it turned out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was a rather unusual rain all night long.
[SPEAKER_01]: It just dripped and dropped.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't a heavy downpour, although when you got up in the morning and looked out at some of the puddles laying around, it seemed like it must have been a lot of water.
[SPEAKER_01]: And maybe it was, but it came rather slowly but steadily.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we were pretty dry in the morning, except Rita had her, what was wet?
[SPEAKER_01]: her blanket.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought it was something else because her blanket was a little bit wet where the little bit of water had gathered into a kind of a gulf on the tent where it sagged a little bit and it began to drip through since it couldn't drain off.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we got up, had our breakfast with eggs and sausage and it was a good breakfast and the rain was pretty much
[SPEAKER_01]: stopped by then, but the clouds were somewhat threatening and it was kind of an on and off proposition throughout the morning.
[SPEAKER_01]: I spent the morning writing in my journal.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what she spent the morning doing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, she reorganized.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did a lot of things which had to be done and had gathered up over the past few days.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then along towards noon,
[SPEAKER_01]: It began to rain again, and we began to put all of our stuff inside.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't a heavy rain, but it was a steady little drizzle.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I hustled off to the headquarters and phoned Bibb Falk.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, it might be kind of muddy out here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And besides, I gave you the wrong direction to get out here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said it was Congress, not Cannon.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we discussed that a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: But by this time, he was much more receptive to my coming to his house.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rita suggested maybe he call Ted Lyons, who guaranteed my credentials.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know, but he was much more receptive to my coming to his house this time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so that was decided upon.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the rain began to get a little bit heavier.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right away was the interview, because
[SPEAKER_01]: Apparently it had something to do with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I later found out he wanted to watch the ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I rushed back to the tent and gathered all my belongings in my little case, the tapes, the recorder, the extension cords, the autographed baseball, the encyclopedia.
[SPEAKER_01]: And off I went.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the rain became heavier as I proceeded northward on Interstate Highway 35 into the heart of downtown
[SPEAKER_01]: Austin, although we bypassed it.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went over it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw the Holiday Inn on the way in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw the Texas football stadium on one side.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw a big round building, which turned out to be the Texas University Coliseum.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't see the Texas University baseball field.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was on the other side, but at a point where the road was rather low, and I couldn't see up to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Big Falk told me about that later.
[SPEAKER_01]: As you see in the tape, it was a $2.5 million college baseball plant, which has to take the cake throughout the country.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a chance to see it this morning with its tartan turf and its 5,000 seat grandstand, the lights, the beautiful layout there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took a few pictures of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: credit to any triple a minor league ball cause there's no question about better than any I've seen maybe not quite as good as The Franklin County Stadium, but better than any other Now so I raced up route 35 to 38 and a half Street is where I cut off and worked my way over to D Avenue or to Speedway Avenue then up to 42nd over to D and up D to Bib Fox house where he
[SPEAKER_01]: who is a bachelor, and his maiden sister, 86 years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's only 79.
[SPEAKER_01]: They lived together there in this little wooden frame house, not very elaborate at all, at the corner of D and 43rd Street.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was sitting out on the porch as I rolled in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hadn't eaten any lunch, so quickly after the phone call, I had bought two large Hershey bars.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I ate those Hershey bars on the way up, jamming them down and not digesting them too well.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that was my lunch.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got my hands into some sticky, the Hershey bars got a little sticky there.
[SPEAKER_01]: My hands are kind of sticky.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I tried to look around in the car.
[SPEAKER_01]: I stopped just before I got to the corner of the street there to look around for a wash and wipe to wipe off the stickiness.
[SPEAKER_01]: But as you might suspect, there was no wash and wipe to be seen anywhere in that car.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were in her gritchel.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went in this interview with sticky hands.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I rolled down slowly and pulled up in front of this house.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there was Bibb Falk out on the front porch waiting for me, walking out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I recognized him instantly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Big, tall, handsome guy, slim.
[SPEAKER_01]: For somebody who's almost 80 years old, how they can retain the almost identical look of youth, it's hard to imagine.
[SPEAKER_01]: We saw Ted Lyons over in Vinton.
[SPEAKER_01]: And with his glasses on, he looked pretty much like the Ted lines of youth.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he took them off, he didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was about four or five years younger than Bibb Falk, or three years younger.
[SPEAKER_01]: Falk didn't have those lines around his eyes.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had that sturdy, upright gait, that clear complexion, all of his hair neatly combed back.
[SPEAKER_01]: A very handsome man.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he came out and greeted me in the street there and wondered where my gear was.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got it out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he held the door as I got it out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we went into the house.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't, as I say, a very impressive house.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it was a house.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was neat.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we sat up in the living room there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there weren't many elaborate furnishings.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I didn't see his sister at all, except one time late in the interview, she came into the dining room, which was the room behind the living room there.
[SPEAKER_01]: to get something when retired back to the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_01]: We sat in adjacent chairs with the recorder in between us, and away we went on this interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was not an easy interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was somewhat restrained.
[SPEAKER_01]: He did warm up a little bit, and he was friendly.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't have too much to say about some things.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some things he wouldn't talk about.
[SPEAKER_01]: The black socks business, he seemed to talk about as much as he knew.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he didn't volunteer a lot of things.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had to kind of keep probing and prying, and sometimes to no avail.
[SPEAKER_01]: Once in a while, I hit something which he would respond to, like Johnny Mossel, Alex Metzler, Charlie Robertson, the no-hit game there, which he did not play, but was on the bench.
[SPEAKER_01]: A little bit on Babe Ruth.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he just, from all I've heard about Bib Fock, the jockey Fock, this kind of a hail fellow well-meant, I thought he would be an outgoing, talkative, really very energetic, enthusiastic person in an easy interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it was not that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had trouble filling up an hour of tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a good bit of the tape was on his college coaching days.
[SPEAKER_01]: which really was of interest generally, but not of my primary concern.
[SPEAKER_01]: I happened to mention the Hall of Fame once or twice.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't want to talk about that, whether he's bitter that he isn't in the Hall of Fame, or he thinks some of the people in there are not worthy of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a couple of things I mentioned, he just seemed to want to close the book on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't want to talk about them.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was quite curt in saying this.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I was a little ill at ease at times in this interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't quite, while my credentials were rather quickly established, I couldn't warm up to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't really exchange ideas and thoughts the way I have in so many of these interviews.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a certain stiffness which prevailed in this, in the course of the interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't completely at ease.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he was probably as friendly as he ever is with anybody who walks in off the street like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm convinced I probably got as much as anyone did from an interview with Bibb Falk.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I just had expected, from what I'd heard, so much more than what I actually got.
[SPEAKER_01]: What are you doing now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: She's spraying the interior of the tent.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is the first interview I've ever commented on in the wide open spaces, I might say.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it's such a beautiful night.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's all dark now.
[SPEAKER_01]: The lights in the camp surrounding us.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it's just a glorious night.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can hear the crickets in the distance, probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we kind of dragged this thing out a couple of times in the interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just almost died.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think I prepared well enough for this.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm sure if I had spent about a half hour going over his record and picking out incidents in his career with the White Sox and with Cleveland, I could have done a better job.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it was spontaneous there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think I'd planned to spend a little time preparing prior to this coming out at 2 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_01]: But then this thing came up so quickly, my going in there, I didn't have time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a few general questions, but I didn't have enough of a specific character.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that could have, I'm sure, enriched the interview had I been a little better prepared for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, after about an hour or so and some hemming and hawing, I said, well, I'd like to take this picture just here at the end of the tape there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I shut the machine off, and I
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I asked to see his sister, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he brought her in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I met her.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she invited me back to the kitchen, where he's got a few pictures up on the wall, but mostly his Texas University coaching career.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was one nice picture of him in a white sex uniform, about a 5 by 7 head shot.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was one good one of his trip to England in 1934, I think it was, or 1924.
[SPEAKER_01]: when he went with the White Sox and the Giants to England.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it shows all of the White Sox lined up, and then Johnny Evers, who was the manager at that time, shaking hands with King George V. And there's the Duke of Wales, the Prince of Wales behind him, and the Duke of York behind him, later Edward VIII and George VI, and a few other dignitaries.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's quite an interesting picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would like to have had that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And about eight or nine White Sox were well-known in that picture also.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I didn't bring my 35-millimeter camera with me, so I couldn't take shots of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he said he didn't have any.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, because he said he didn't have any.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd gone to the Texas Hall of Fame or the, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have a feeling he just discounted a lot of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would not even have seen those few pictures in the back of the kitchen had his sister not mentioned them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I was back there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took his picture, holding up one of his own pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I asked his sister to take a picture of us.
[SPEAKER_01]: But she's got very poor eyesight.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she was holding the camera about a foot away from her head and said she couldn't see the little viewfinder through which she was supposed to gaze.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, well, maybe you can get kind of a general view there.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, their camera's waving up and down and she wasn't looking very close.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Bib Fock rather abruptly says, can you see us?
[SPEAKER_01]: She says, no, I can't see you too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then he said, don't click it then.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he marched out of the room.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thought he was very rude and abrupt.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I didn't see him again for about, I chatted with her for about five or 10 minutes.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I finally went out and he was watching the baseball game in the living room.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's abrasive a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: warm, the way I thought he would be.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we watched the baseball game a little bit there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd actually autographed my ball before the interview began, so that was taken care of.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I took a couple pictures of him sitting down in the chair there we were, but I think the light was bad, and they may not come out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so I departed, and he walked out to the car with me, and he told me about how bad it was on I-35 going back to camp when it was raining.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was pleasant, congenial.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe because I was leaving, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I got there probably around 1.20 or so and left probably about 2.40.
[SPEAKER_01]: So it was a little over an hour interview and all the other things in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: As I say, I was not
[SPEAKER_01]: happy with the interview, but at least I saw Bibb Falk.
[SPEAKER_01]: I met him and talked with him and found out that you couldn't get a better interview than the one I got.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then it was pouring rain coming back.
[SPEAKER_01]: It got very heavy and I said, I'm sure, I thought to myself, I'm sure glad it isn't raining like this out at the KOA campground.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I finally pulled into the campground, and I had trouble finding our tent.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was water all around.
[SPEAKER_01]: The tent was practically underwater, at least part of it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tooted the horn, wondering where Rita was, if she was swimming in the water or gone to some other place.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she appeared rather tattered and torn out from the entry.
[SPEAKER_01]: holding something that she was saving from the water, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Toothbrush, maybe.
[SPEAKER_01]: But right away, I realized that a crisis had occurred.
[SPEAKER_01]: And something had to be done quickly.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the tent itself was, the interior was dry for the most part.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if you walked on the floor, you were on about six inches of water.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the tent floor went up and down with each step.
[SPEAKER_01]: As you heard, the water underneath, the tent stakes at that edge of the tent were fully submerged, all four of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the water was seeping in through the seams at the bottom there and a little bit into the tent.
[SPEAKER_01]: She had everything up on the chairs and the cots we had in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was vaguely reminiscent of our sojourn in
[SPEAKER_01]: New York State in 1964, that bad rainy night at the World's Fair, remember, where the water was coming in all over the place.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had about one square yard in the middle where four miserable people were huddled, two little squalling brats then.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was raining all over the place.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how we ever lived through that night.
[SPEAKER_01]: We sure got out of there the next day, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, well, this has nothing to do with the interview, but since I have a lot of tape to use up here, I might as well continue on to describe this miserable afternoon.
[SPEAKER_01]: We began taking things out of the tent to high ground.
[SPEAKER_01]: To the rear of our area, the ground inclined upward.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there was a rather nice grassy spot there we could move everything to, although it was not shady.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I just quickly sent Rita off to the telephone to get a motel for the night, because we were not going to stay in that place another night.
[SPEAKER_01]: But as we were removing all of the interior material to the exterior, the sun broke through.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then the sky became blue.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it became warm and beautiful and sunny.
[SPEAKER_01]: Beautiful afternoon.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we began to have second thoughts about going to that $30 motel up the road.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we had till 6 o'clock to declare ourselves.
[SPEAKER_01]: We did have a motel room saved till 6 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we decided to wait and see.
[SPEAKER_01]: clear out the tent, for one thing, and take the tent down and dry it out if we could.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we did that.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got everything out.
[SPEAKER_01]: We pulled the tent.
[SPEAKER_00]: We managed to get the tent down without too much more water getting into it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rita has something to say here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, not really.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just that it was so tough.
[SPEAKER_00]: We took down the dry end first.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then while we both held up the end of the other, the wet end, we collapsed it and quickly pulled it over on dry ground.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because it was just half the tent that was under water.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you for that description.
[SPEAKER_01]: OK, now we got the tent over on dry ground.
[SPEAKER_01]: And with the bottom side up.
[SPEAKER_01]: and the sun blazing down in beautiful warmth.
[SPEAKER_01]: The bottom of that tent was dry in about 10 minutes, probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: So then we flipped it over and dried the rest of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And meanwhile, drying all of our drop cloths, which were soaked, our towels, which were soaked.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, one towel will never be the same.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not sure what color it is now, but it's not what it was originally.
[SPEAKER_01]: We dried out the tent case.
[SPEAKER_01]: bag, the tent pole bag, ourselves, and everything else.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we had enough room to dry these things.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it kept getting nicer and beautiful.
[SPEAKER_01]: Blue sky all over the place now towards 4 o'clock, 4.30.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we even had time to sit down and sip a beer and a Pepsi Cola or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: And life looked beautiful again.
[SPEAKER_01]: So
[SPEAKER_02]: We had to make a decision.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had till 6 o'clock and I finally made this bold decision that we would stay.
[SPEAKER_01]: We would re-set our tent in this dry area.
[SPEAKER_01]: Meanwhile, that area we evacuated was still under a foot of water practically.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was the lowest, I think it's the lowest plot of ground in Texas, or South Texas, wherever South Texas is.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we set the tent up, and it dried out nicely.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the interior was nice and dry.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they put everything back in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was beautiful the rest of the evening.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had a nice sleep there last night.
[SPEAKER_01]: And got up all chipper today to tear off to Austin and see the town.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got up this morning and had breakfast.
[SPEAKER_01]: packed everything, took the tent down, put it up on the roof.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had the biggest roof we ever had.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what we put up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't do before.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I thought it was going up to the sky somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Somebody passed by and says, you've got a big load there, don't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: And so we got off about 9 o'clock or so, went into Austin, drove around.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got out to this ballpark Bibb Falk described, took a few pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: That is a fantastic setup.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we drove back over to the university and got a picture of the football field, the LBJ library, the Texas Tower, and wandered around a little bit back through town, took a picture of the Capitol, and then down the road to 290 out to Fredericksburg, which is where we are now.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were going to talk about that other interview you had.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that goes on the other tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: That goes on my other tape, but I just put that one in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we passed the Elgin.